Jean Carlos Medina Gonzalez

Kissimmee, Florida 34741

Phone: (786) 426-5577 | Email: datajcmg@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jcmg | GitHub: https://github.com/JCMedinaG

Portfolio: https://jcmedinag.github.io/Portfolio

Professional Summary

Industrial Engineer with more than 10 years of experience in data analytics and visualization, and a strong knowledge of statistical methods, data gathering, and analysis. Comfortable with tools like Excel, Python, SQL, R, SAS, Machine Learning, and Tableau. Proven technical and leadership abilities in data warehousing, data healthcare, and data management environments. Passionate about data analytics and learning new technologies. Getting on track after 2 months of family caring and time off.

Technical Skills

Programming and Software: Python, R, Excel, Pandas, SAS, Tableau, Project, Visio, Microsoft Office, Surfer, Machine Learning.

Databases: SQL.

Version Control: GitHub.

Data Skills: Mining, Processing, Cleaning, Modeling, Visualization, ETL.

Other Skills: Preventive Maintenance, Logistics Management, Health and Safety, Operations Management, Cost Savings, Process Improvement, Quality Assurance, Business Analytics, Project Planning, Creative Problem Solving, Supply Chain Management, Quality Control, Task Management, Transportation Management, Purchasing, Teaching, Project Management.

Certifications

Applied Machine Learning

Issuing authority: Columbia Engineering

Issued date: June 2019

Expiration Date: No Expiration date

See credential

SAS Programming for R Users

Issuing authority: SAS Issued date: Apr 2019

Expiration date: No Expiration Date

See credential

\bullet SAS Statistics 1: Introduction to ANOVA, Regression, and

Logistic Regression Issuing authority: SAS Issued date: Apr 2019

Expiration date: No Expiration Date

See credential

• SAS Programming 1: Essentials

Issuing authority: SAS Issued date: Mar 2019

Expiration date: No Expiration Date

See credential

UCF Data Analytics & Visualization Boot Camp

Issuing authority: UCF Continuing Education

Issued date: Mar 2019

Expiration date: No Expiration Date

See credential

Projects

- **Plotly.js-Project:** Developed an interactive dashboard to explore a unique Belly Button Biodiversity Dataset, employing JavaScript and Plotly, and hosted on Heroku. See details
- Leaflet.js-Project: Built a visualization dashboard showing all earthquakes from 7 days ago updating weekly, implementing JavaScript, Leaflet.js, and hosted on GitHub. See details
- HTML-Project: Design a website using HTML, CSS, and coupled with NASA weather data, resulting in a visualization webpage of big recent meteorological singularities. See details

- Tableau-Project: Performed and analysis of New York City Bike dataset, generating an interactive dashboard with visualization techniques. See details
- Redesign of the Program of Occupational Health and Safety-Project: Established an observation guide to perform a vulnerability analysis and applied corrective actions as needed. See details

Experience

Family Care and Time Off • Kissimmee, FL.

✓ Online training to get Tableau 10 certification.

11/2019-2020

✓ Set up a regular workspace to manage and keep updating Portfolio, LinkedIn and GitHub.

Lincoln Property Company • Orlando, FL.

Building Engineer 2017-2019

Accomplishments:

✓ Took part in designing a preventive maintenance plan for identification of needed repairs or actions required to prevent damage to equipment and structures utilizing Excel and Tableau as analytics and visualizations tools respectively.

Diamond Resorts International - Orlando, FL.

Engineering Technician 2015-2017

Accomplishments:

✓ Led on bettering safety levels, particularly to chemicals and several dangerous goods employing and analyzing saved data, and Excel to analyze progression.

Maracaibo Polyclinic • Maracaibo, Venezuela

Health and Safety Engineer 2013-2015

Accomplishments:

- ✓ Recommended changes and alterations of processes to increase safety and health outlooks.
- Exhibit strong leadership skills combined with engineering principles to control safety and health initiatives.

PDVSA • Maracaibo. Venezuela

Logistics Engineer 2012-2013

Accomplishments:

- ✓ Integrated supply chain, warehousing, and logistics operations into production processes as part of a 20-member operations team; negotiated agreements to forge partnerships with 3 logistics service providers.
- ✓ Training a small team in developing effective stocking and inventory-management systems to minimize loss and maximize performance.

Intermica • Maracaibo, Venezuela

Geologist 2009-2012

Accomplishments:

- ✓ Generate and create geologic maps and cross sections to improve mines development and production.
- ✓ Utilize basic scientific principles, theories, practices and existing technologies to refine solutions for technical problems with limited scope.

Education

Data Analytics and Visualization Boot Camp 2019

University of Central Florida • Orlando, Florida

Bachelor of Science in Industrial Engineering 2013

Rafael Urdaneta University • Maracaibo, Venezuela

Associate of Science in Geology 2005

Maracaibo University Institute of Technology • Maracaibo, Venezuela